谨以此片追忆逝去的童年，如果你也有这样的童年的话欢迎加入我们的贴吧"神剑传奇"。本作品之片源来自互联网，版权归原公司所有。任何组织和个人不得公开传播或用于任何商业盈利用途，一切后果由该组织或个人承担！制作者不承担任何法律及连带责任！请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
France 2, Ecipse Animation, Tooncan Paodeczions Xll Inc
Fr
eipe五n
XIl Ine
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
SCRipt oy
enjamin LegRand
校对：
SCRipt oy
Everybody up! Time to go
大家起来吧该出发了
always hate
to leave this,place
lused to. mee
your father here, Djana
裘咖我曾经在这里遇到你父亲
This. where
saw hina-for the last time
就是在这里最后一次见到他
N
That day everything
could have change
那天原本可以改切的
It's always a
pleasure to see you. Tara
见到你真荣幸塔拉
It would be if we didn't
have to hide Prince Erwann
如果我们不需要再躲藏
就再好不过了伊万亲王
You must persuade
your leader to meet him
必须劝服你们的首领来见艾德温国王
我必须劝服你们的首领辣见艾德温国王
Take this as a
token of my friendship
这个作为表达我诚意的信物
For one moment
seemed we could have peace
真的感觉我们可以拥有和平
Ee wene- so close.
我们离得如此近
Watch out!
小心
第？集
harge! Give them no quarter!
进攻不要给他们喘息的时间
了
Tara!
塔拉你
Balls of- fire, fly!
球去
If I catch, you.
you are grilled meat
要是我抓到你就把你烧成烤肉
Y
Tara! Tara answer me
塔拉塔拉回答我
She is just dazed
她只是昏过去了
She needs energy-boosting plants
她需要能量补充草
rpad will know which ones
阿帕德知道这种草的
back before you know it
你搞漓楚是什么之前我就会回来的
The barbarians
蛮族人来了
Where is your leader?
你们的首领在哪
I'm the leader. Please!
我是求你们
Please.
求你了
The Regent Bragan has
already taken almost all we had!
拉刚亲王已经征收了我们大部分粮食
You lie! Tell me where
you have hidden your harvest,
你撒谎告诉我粮食藏在哪
or you will regret it!
否则你会后悔的
You will be struck by bad luck!
你会走霉运的
I have seen the signs
我看到征兆了
What you haven't seen
my poor Zoldan It's me!
可怜的佐登你看到什么了啊是我
u
三
身
Seven against one
She's crazy
她是疯了
Djana! Always getting in my way!
裘娜你老是坏我的事
Your way, Zek?
西克是坏你的事吗
Has Wolf retired
to let you in charge
不是沃尔夫退休把大权交给你了啊
Don't listen to her. Zek
The Spirits are with you!
别听她的西克神会保佑你的
Leave everything
the way you found it, Zek
西克把所有抢来的东西放下
and I'll settle
this with the real chief
那我就只追究主犯的责任
f
SU
Surprise
惊喜吧
③
Insolent little
没礼貌的小
A
Tara! Can- you hear me?
塔拉能听到我说话吗
A Shogi
哪来的法师
哪来的去师
A Shogi
哪来的法师
A Sory
What's the matter with you?
你怎么了
Silence!
给我安静点
I won't let you- cast another
of your Shogi spells on m
我不会再让有有机会对我下
A spell? Tara, you
know Shogis don' t cast spells.
咒吗塔拉你知道法师是不会下咒的
And I would not cast one on you!
况我不会对你下咒啊
No magic spells?
不是魔咒吗
Then how did a pip-squeak
like you get me down
那还会有其他什么无聊的人把我敲晕呢
nd why didn' t I even remember it?
而且为什么我一点都记不起来了
s this how you did
你是利用这本书做到的吧
Abook-of-your-nasty
Shogi magic trick
这本书里都是些法师的流幻术吧
No Tara! Not the Book - of Life!
不要塔拉不关生命之书的事
Give it back
Don't you recognize me?
把它还给我你不认识我了吗
said, keep quiet!
我说过给我安静点
Another blade
won't-help you, Zed
西克再来一次也是徒劳
Evens without Xcalibur
aIcan outfight you all day.
助使没有神剑一整天下来
我都可以打败你
Another blade
won't help you, Zed
酉克/再来一次也是徒劳
Eves
bur
以打地
Even without Xcalibur
can outfight you all day
即使没有神剑一整天下来
我都可以打败你
but I haven t got all day
不过我没时间跟你玩了
=
Now take your men and leave
before-I get really angry
趁我没有真正发怒之前带你的人离开
get even
我会找你算账的
Ha! They all say that
哈他们就会那样说≥
恰他们就会那样说
Ha! They all say that
哈他们就会那样说
会
Thank you, Princess
多谢了公主殿下
i don' t think Wolf was
behind this attack, Arpad
阿帕德我认为这次袭击
不是沃尔夫下的命令
I'll talk to him
我会跟他说这事的
but first I need some
healing herbs for Tara
但是我现在需要一点草药给塔拉
She was knocked unconscious
她被敲晕了
I'll get some
我去拿点过来
分
Someday, I'll get even
总有一天我会找你算帐的
Someday. Maybe today, Zek
总有一天吗也许今天就可以啊西克
The spirits are with you
神会保佑你的
That's what you
said in the village!
你在村子里就说过那话了
Tara has been hurt
塔拉受伤
f she die
如果塔拉死
it could be made to look
like it was Djana's fault
就可以推说是裘娜的过错
If Wolf believed that
要是沃尔夫信以为真
This way, we follow Djaha's trail
走这边我们跟着裘娜
Tara?
塔拉
A
Herik?
哈里克你们在
Where could they have gone?
他们会去哪呢
The horses tracks lead this way
马的脚印朝这边去的
What could have
gotten- into them?
他们是不是碰到什么麻烦了
Come on, Eole
快走风神
会
Oh, by all the devils of the sea
以海中恶魔的名义
Too late
来晚了
The Book of Life!
This will change everything
是生命之书这会让一切都改变的
Tara! What a surprise!
塔拉见到你真是惊喜
Is this a joke?
这是在开玩笑吗
Why=is Herik tied up-like that?
为什么哈里克被绑成那样
Since when do
nee
d
a reason to, tie \up a Shogi?
绑个法师还需要理由吗
And how do you know his name?
而且你怎么知道叫也佛么名字的啊
而且你怎么知道叫他么字的
And, how do you know his name?
而且你怎么知道叫
名字的啊
而且你怎么知道叫他什么字的啊
now do you? know his name?
而且你怎么知道叫他
的啊
而且你怎知道叫他什以名字的两
And, how do you know his name
而且你怎么知道叫他什么名字的啊
pua noM Isol noNane
Have ' you lost your mind?
你是不是糊涂了啊
Herik is my son!
Untie him at once.
哈里克是我儿子马上给他松绑
Your son?
他是你儿子吗
That,s impossible!
Your son, a Shogi?.
不可能你儿子个法师吗
Have you lost=your memory?
你是不是失去忆了
Yes, father,she has
是的父亲她是失去记忆
We were ambushed
and she took a blow to the head
我们中埋
她脑门被敲了一重记
TA
isten -Tara. try to remember
听我说塔拉努力回想一下
we were on the Wandering City
我们在漂流之城的明
have a surprise for you Wolf
沃尔夫我送你
惊喜
Tara! This is a real family reunion
塔拉这真是家庭团聚啊
Well, Tara! Meet my son
塔拉来见见我儿子
Your. your son?
我是你儿子吗
我是你哪
Your, your son?
我是你
What's this new
me Wolf?
这又是什么
It's no scheme
不是么把
the truth
uth!
s the truth
这是真的
I gave this medallion to your
mother on the day we were married
结婚当天我把这圆形徽章送给你母亲的
h
汕see
yu see
你看
YOurs
看
言的
I had it engraved\ with
the eterna
hs of spouses.
我在上面刻夫妻永恒的构
e
一不记得了
on't remember that at all.
我一点都不记得了
D
n别
Don't worry
别担心
tEven-if you don't
remember it, /Tara
塔拉即使你不记得这个
you must know that I wouldn
e about Herik- being my son
你也知道我不
骗你
才说哈里克是我儿子
don t know what to believe
我不知道该相信什么才对
长
She had a blow on the head
有人在她脑门敲了一记
Part of her
memory has been erased,
她的部分记忆被抹去了
but I think I can cure her
不过我想能治好她
There's someone coming
有人过来了
Herik!- Is everything alright?
哈里克
Why did you leave the clearing
为什么你们要离开林的觉时
Is Tara better
塔拉好点了吗
ot really, no. What kept you
没有什么事让你耽搁
I was held
我被拖住了
Wolf, your men attacked
the villagers of-Quinn
沃尔夫你的人袭击了全恩的村民
Zek! He was supposed
to barter. not plunder!
死的西克叫他去物物交换
没叫他去抢劫
have the plants
you wanted for -Fara
我把治疗塔拉的草药带来
They won't help now
现在用不上
Physically she is fine
她的身体没事
It's her memory
that is the problem
她的记忆出了问题
What
什么
She does not know us, Djana
她不认识我们了裘娜
She thinks she is
still raiding. with Wolf.
她认为她还是跟沃尔夫一起呢
That is crazy!
太扯了吧
Is there any way
to get her memory back?
有办法让她恢复记忆吗
Yeah… think so
我想应该有
Everyone leaves a psychic
imprint on objects they touched
每个人在接触过的东西上和去过的地方
a trace of/what they'vealived
也就是对他们生活的追忆
We will take Tara
to familiar places
我们可以带塔拉去她熟悉的地方
in/ hope that she
can rediscover herself
希望那样能她自己恢复记忆
Well as long as
she is not physically hurt.
既然她身体没有大碍
I'm not sure that Idon't
prefer her the way / she is now
我不觉得她现在这样有什么不好啊
What's with your father?
你父亲怎么
He almost did not
let Tara go with you!
他很不愿意让塔拉跟我们一起走
He just prefers
old Tara, that's
他只是更喜欢以前的那个塔拉仅此而已
' Are yousure
you canhelp her?
你确定你可以帮到她吗
With the Book of Life. sure
有生命之书帮忙当然可以
ust hope it
still where Tara tossed
塔拉把生命之书丢出
我只希
在那个地
Spirits of the air
and time, come to my aid
空气和时间之神请帮助我吧
Alright. Zoldan
we have waited long enough!
干得不错佐登我们等得够久了
Inspire my vision
请开启我的天眼吧
Griffins! Watch out!
有怪兽小心
了
一
What is going on?
怎么回事
You invoke forces you know
nothing about, miserable human!
愚蠢的人类你居然对自己
唤醒的力量一无所知
Oh, master of
darkness, forgive me
噢黑暗之王请饶恕我
You will serve me!
你会为我效劳的
Take the book of
life to the Regent
把生命之书送去给摄政王
He will make you
the grand shaman
他会让你成为这个王国的大巫师
Thank you, master!
多谢您主
I will grant you some
small powers to protect you
你连个自保的法力都没有
until you reach the palace
我赐予你一点小法力
as you have none of your own
确保你平安到达王宫
Back off!
滚回去
just saved your life
西克我可是救了你
Another humiliation!
耻辱
Look, Tara: one of your friends
看塔拉你的一个朋友
Zek, the famous thug
西克出了名的恶棍
That's one face
do remember, little dragon
小龙宝贝我还真记得那张脸
and itis one I
id forgetting
不
记那
The Book of Life?
/Did you found it
你是不是找到生命之书了
Zoldan had
佐登把它拿走
he even used it-to
conjure up those Griffins
他甚至利用生命之书召来了那些怪兽
then ran away
然后自己跑了
Griffins from the Book of, Life?
那些怪兽来自生命之书吗
That can't be rigbt
那不对啊
They could only
come from Kwodah
那些怪兽肯定是科沃达派来的
We have got to
find Zoldan, and fast!
我们得去找佐登快
will find that
miserable old frog
我会找到那个愚蠢的老青蛙的
Zoldan! Stop! Come back!
佐登站住回来
会
彡
E
The clearing did not
trigger any memories for Tara
树林空时地没让塔拉回想起任何东西
Maybe we should try an object
也许我们可以拿件物品试试
My father's dagger
我父王的短剑
Tara! Take a look at your dagger
拉看看你的
Itis the one my father gave)you
是我父王给你的
s导
The first time we met you
我们第一次见你的时候
Herik and I were
ethe Royal Palace
哈里克和我在王宫里
about to enter,Bragan's chamber.
正准进布拉刚的宫
Try to remember, ara
下塔拉
This is it
就是这里
My father's dagger
我父王的短剑
The Barbarian!
是蛮族人
Bragan is behind
this door. Come quick
布拉刚就在这扇门后面快跟我来
Maybe you prefer
Bragan's secret passage, Herik?
也许你可以走布刚的
秘密通道哦哈里
I hope you dont expect us to
你不是希望我们从这里去吧
你不是希我以致下去吧
thope you donat expect us to
你不鼎践们从里下去吧
Well? What are you waiting for?
还在等
You helped us escape!
你都我们逃出了王
trusted you because
my father gave you his dagger
我父王想短剑涂你所以我相信你
ur father?
你父王
Yes Prince Erwann
是的就是伊万亲王
He was your friend
他是你的朋友
Erwann
伊万吗
No, it doesn't ring a bell
什么也想不起来
Well
you can keep the dagger.
你保管这把短剑叫
吧
have had enough of this
我受够了
I'mgoing to find
Wolf, and sail away
我去找呀尔夫然后回海上
with or without myerm'emories
管他有
Zoldan is nearly
at the Roval Palace
佐登快到王宫了
I tried to stop him.
我试图阻止他
But it was no use
但是没用
He would not listen to me
他不会听我的
He must be trying to get
the book of life to Bragan
他肯定是想把生命之书交给布拉
We have got to get it back
我们得把生命之书拿回来
留
That will be tough
那会有点困难
And our friend
ara never let us down
我们的朋友塔拉
when things got tough
从来不会在遇到困难的时候
抛弃我们不管
Ah! Give me back my dagger.
哦地剑还给我
Well, I think I did a great job.
我觉得自己干得不错
Pretty brave and daring,
if I do say so myself
可以说我很勇敢
L人
The Royal Palace
d到上
The- Royal Pa
Ah, the Regent
has sent me an escort
摄政王派护卫过来了
Remember the Regent's orders
记得摄政王的命令吧
Just take the Book.
and get rid of the old fool
拿到生命之书后把这老笨蛋干掉
I am Zoldan!
And the Regent is expecting me
我是佐登摄政王在等着见我
Master Kwodahn! Help me
科沃达主人救我
Balls of fire
火球去
I
e
是
One of these days, somebody
is going to lose this Book
这些天有人老是把生命之书弄丢了
Where is that
stupid Zoldan gone?
阝个愚盒的佐登去哪
I'll find him
我去找他
m beginning to get the knack
我开始找到诀窍了
You have failed me. Zoldan!
你失信于我了佐登
Master
主人
I can explain everything
我可以解释的
Nol-You have wasted
enough of my time
不用你已经浪费我够多时间了
Imagine being turned
into an ugly little beast
想想变成一只丑陋的小动物有多可怜
Let's try the clearing again
我们再去空旷地试试
With the Book of Life
有了生命之书
should be able to get
Tara back her memory this time
这次我应该可以帮塔拉找回记忆
Good idea. Herik
好主意哈里克
The sooner, the better
越快越好
Riders!
骑兵过来了
We have to lose them
我们得甩掉他们
Ah! I understand what
you are up to, little Shogi
我知道你要干什么小术士
T
Here it
就是这里
r'm going to use the Book of Life
塔拉我现在开始使用生命之书
to enhance the psychic imprint
that you left here, Tara
帮你把留在这里的记忆放大
片这样应该可以把你的记忆找采
It should bring back your memory
这样应该可以把你的记忆找回来
多
d人
Book of Life!
生命之书
May your infinite knowledge
help restore Tara's entire memory
愿你无穷的智慧帮助储存塔拉全部的记
Found you at last!
终于找到你们了
You won' t believe what Zoldan
你们肯定不会相信佐登被变成什么了
Not now, wvip
威普等下再说
T
My head
我的头
What's happening? I:,. see
发生什么事了我看到
see image
我看到了一些图象
Come on, Tara! Remember
加油塔拉全部想起来吧
es! remember being here
是的我来过这里
It's coming back to me
记忆回来了
Erwann., a fine man!
伊万个好男人
It is working!
成功了
buIyJoM S! lI
She is beginning to remember
她开始想起来了
Look!
看
Yes. She is
beginning to remember.
是的她开始想起来了
But what will she remember?
可她会想起什么呢
Balls of fire
火球去
Leave Tara alone!
不要碰塔拉
She's mine now!
And I'll use her to destroy your
现在她是我的了我会利用她消灭你
N
g
Now I know who your are
现在我知道你是谁
Walka. the witch!
你是沃卡那个女巫
Kwodahn put a false
memory in your head!
科沃达把假的记忆植入你脑中了
今
ara
不要塔拉
Alright, I believe you
行我相信你
Like heck i do!
我在做什么啊
Erwann,s dagger!
伊万的短剑
It is our only hope to
get Tara's true memory back
这是我们找回塔拉记忆的唯一希望了
Herik! Help!
哈里克帮我
三
Erwann's dagge
这是伊万的短剑
He gave it to me as a
token of peace, of frienship
他把短剑送给我以示诚意
can't say I'm glad you
have your memory, back, Tara
塔拉你找回记忆我不能说很高兴
For a moment, I hoped
you would return to us.
曾经一度我很希望你回来
I still serve the
people of thesea, Wolf
沃尔夫我还是为海上枭雄效劳啊
Just in a different way
只是用不同的方式
Like Zek here
就象西克那样
Yes, Zek has had
a change of duties
是的西克的职责变动
And Zoldan is missing
佐登也消失了
My crew keeps getting smaller
when we visit these shores
下次登岸的时候我的人要更少
公
It's zoldan!
I saw Kwodahn transform him!
是佐登我看见科沃达把他变成那样的
We can't leave
him like that. Herik!
我们不能任凭他那样不管哈里克
Sure you can, why not?
当然可以不管为什么不呢
Book of Life
destroy the illusions
生命之书请破除幻象吧
so that truth may reveal itself.
还佐登真面目
台
Get on board, brave shaman!
上船吧勇敢的萨满教人
We have a few things.
to discuss, you and 1.
我和你还有些事情要讨论呢
Goodbye, Father!
再会父亲
And don't worry
I won't forget you this time
别担心这次我不会忘记你的
xecuTIve sT
EDITOR
ScrIPT SuPeKTISO宽
erect
EDITOR
ScRIPT SUPERTISOR
EKCCUTI
R7 COTTOR,
AUDE DIHE
OH TORT EDITOR
积5
De式
sTD属 Gei. elLPse
TS
STUDIO MKNI6
FLLOT
PRODUCTION XOMIMISTRA TOR- TOONCIH PKOOUCTIONS XIl INC.
STUDIO MAN
PRODUCTION DMIMUTRAT。宽
PRODUCTION KDMINSTRX TOK- TOONCKH PRODUCTION ll
ON AAKAGE
3D- MODELIN∈
3D MODELING
GRIBOUILLE
∈ bOUilLE
orge
PRODUCTION ISSISTINT
PRODUCTION YECKETIRY
PERTLSORs
延Rm
器1
SuPERTISORS
6T15
写xRTs
ID MODe1
要8
C6 IKTISTS
DErie
MOTION CAPTURE
THIL
C6CG INC
CGC6 INC
需后四
PRODUCTIOH PERvISOR
CGCG INC
execu SHo uceR
NOn
CGCG INC
RCON SUN
LITOuT a
SUPERYLSOR
xoc5enso
LAY-OUT C AN
mour a jesse ten sureansor
HETwOR瓦
L.ouT ar
recr段
NETWORT ADMINISTRITION MRNKGRR
A
翻译：英语辅导频道
输入/时间轴/压制：harry159821/黑月
校对：